Guide to the Brooklyn letterhead collection BCMS.0008
Brooklyn Collection
- Goubeaud, Charles, 1886
  Stable. Better known as Charles Cooper. 850 and 852 Atlantic Avenue near Vanderbilt Avenue
- Goulding's Brooklyn & Long Island Business Directory, 1869
  Publisher. 10 Spruce Street, NY
- Gowen, Michael, 1899
  Horseshoer. 49 N. 6th Street near Kent Avenue
- Grady, J.P. & Co., 1879
  Seafood dealer. 1397 Atlantic Avenue
- Graham, Charles, 1893
  Chemical pottery works. 110 to 132 Metropolitan Avenue
- Graham Distributors, Inc., 1960-1961
  Toys, school and office supplies. 53 Graham Avenue
- Grahlfs, Herman, 1884
  Provision dealer [grocer]. 59 & 61 Prospect Street
- Grammich, Richard / R. Grammich's Son, 1884
  Truck and furniture manufacturer. 103 N. 1st Street
- Grand Army of the Republic, 1899
  Memorial and Executive Committee
- Grand Central Hat & Fur Store, 1879
  Hats and fur. 595 Fulton Street
- Grand Court of the State of New York
  Foresters of America, Office of Grand Chief Ranger James T. Kelly. 2428 Ralph Street
- Grashorn, Henry, Inc., 1944
  Gardening supplies [?]. 1106 Surf Avenue opposite Luna Park
- Graves, R.J., 1883
  Painter and Paper Hanger / Window Shades & Fixtures. 397 Flatbush Ave near Prospect Place
- Greason & Howland, 1883, 1887
  Coal distributor. Office, 33 Atlantic Avenue / Yard, Columbia & Baltic Streets
- Great Atlantic and Pacific Tea Co., The, 1896
  Tea. 598 Fifth Ave corner Prospect Ave
- Green, J.H. & Sons, 1896
  Sauce manufacturer. 148 & 150 Flushing Avenue, cor. Vanderbilt
- Green, John J. / Quincy Granite Works, 1874
  Vault and monument maker. 24th and 25th streets near 5th Ave
- Green, William, 1878
  Real estate and insurance. 185 Fourth Street
- Greenblatt's Economy Store, 1918
  Clothing. 1318 Avenue U
- Greene, I.F., 1882
  Underwear maker. 229, 235 Fulton St.
- Greene Roofing Co., 1938
  Roofing. 2129 Flatbush Ave
- Greenfield Electrical Supply Corp., 1937
  Electrical supply. 1609 Bedford Avenue
- Greenpoint Savings Bank, 1965
  Greenpoint office, 807 Manhattan Avenue, at Calyer Street
- Greenpoint Savings Bank, 1970
  Flushing office, 41-60 Main Street, at Sanford Avenue
- Gregory, Joseph & Co., 1881
  Plumber and gas fitter. 509 DeKalb Avenue
- Gregory, Thomas K., 1861
  Decorator and painter. 280 Court St., between President and Union
- Grening, Paul C., 1888-1889
  Real estate and insurance. 420 Gates Avenue, near Nostrand; 1161 Fulton Street
- Grennell, John C., 1881, 1890
  Paint dealer. 536 Fulton Street; 19 and 21 Flatbush Avenue
- Grenz & Hustedt, 1907
  Painters, decorators, supplies. 95 Tompkins Avenue, near Myrtle Avenue
- Grieb, J.H., 1877, 1880, 1881
  Heaters and house furnishings. 1311 Fulton Ave.; 355 Flatbush Ave.
- Griffin, A.S., 1879
  Roofer. 161 Court Street
- Griffin, H.R., 1880
  Dentist. 675 Myrtle Avenue
- Griffin, P., 1883
  Horseshoer. 83 Smith Street
- Griffith, L.I., 1885
  Ice dealer. 162 Wythe Avenue
- Gritlefeld, Lewis, 1890
  Glass dealer. 592 Fulton St., bet. Navy and Ashland Pl.
- Grogan, Thomas, 1870, 1872, 1873, 1876
  Metal worker. 308 Van Brunt Street and William
- Groppe, John, 1871, 1890
  Coal and wood dealer. 308 and 310 First Street, bet. N 1st and N. 2nd; 788 Grand Street, junction Metropolitan Ave., Newtown Creek; 213 & 215 Kent Ave., bet. N 1st & N. 2nd
- Grosser, Paul, 1886
  Stationer and printer. 520 Fulton Street
- Gruber, F. Jos. & Son, 1884
  Painters. 702 Third Avenue, corner of 44th Street
- Grusczinsky, Harris, 1879
  Looking glass dealer. 98 Atlantic Street, bet. Henry and Hicks
- Guilfoyle, A., 1892
  China and house goods. 667-1/2 Bedford Avenue, bet. Madison and Monroe Streets
- Guinan, Peter, 1894
  Bell hanger and locksmith. 329 Cumberland Street, corner Fulton
- Gulf Oil Corporation, 1944
  Oil dealer. Gardner & Maspeth Avenues, Greenpoint
- Gumbrecht, Bernhard, 1910
  Butcher's outfitter. 76 Sumner Avenue, near Myrtle Ave.
- Gumpel, J. & Son, 1915, 1923
  Clothiers. 362-364 Fulton Street
- Gumpert, S. Co., Inc., 1930
  Food products maker. Bush Terminal
- Guner, Martin, 1879
  Furniture dealer. 87 to 93 Devoe Street, corner Leonard
- Gunning & Foley, 1874, 1878
  Plumbers, steam and gas fitters. 100 Orange Street
- Gunning, Geo. C. & Son, 1888
- Gunther, Felix, 1888-1889
  Metal worker. 579, 675 DeKalb Avenue, near Marcy
- Gur Aryeh Institute for Advanced Jewish Scholarship, 1966
  School. 1355, 1373 President St.
- Gustavson, G.E., 1913
  Upholsterer and cabinet maker. 136 Seventh Avenue
- Gutierrez, Ed. S., 1881
  Ballast master. foot Court St. and 20th St.
- Haaf & Fletcher, 1908
  Plumbers and gas fitters. 918 Myrtle Avenue
- Haag, Otto H., 1900, 1910
  Paper, wood, and twine. Warerooms, 234 Calyer Street/Paper dealer. 194 Monitor Street
- Haff, Stephan, 1895
  Corn brooms and brushes. 132 Boerum Street
- Hahl's
  Tailor. 2103 Avenue C
- Hake, A.V., 1894
  Embalming compound manufacturer. 33 Vanderbilt Street
- Halbert, George, 1896, 1898
  Interior decorations. 455 Fulton Street
- Hall, A.M., 1889
  Painter and decorator. 851 Bedford Avenue
- Hall, Chas. A., 1901
  Contractor and builder. 18th Avenue and 63rd Street
- Hall, Geo. H., 1886
  Butcher. 1665 Fulton St.
- Hall & Hurlbert, Inc., 1900, 1907
  Shipsmiths, machinists and boilermakers. foot of 24th Street; branch shop, West 8th Street, Coney Island
- Hall, James, 1879
  Monumental sculptor. South entrance, Cypress Hills Cemetery
- Hall, James P., 1874
  Plumbing, gas, and steam fitting; heaters. 199 Smith Street
- Hall, Robert S., 1897, 1900
  Lumber dealer. 1760 Fulton and 713 Herkimer Streets
- Hallam, Erastus, 1886
  Carpenter and builder. 235 13th St
- Halleron & O'Brien, 1959
  Attorneys. 189 Montague Street
- Halpin, C.J., 1920
  Ice dealer. 886 New York Avenue
- Hamburg Savings Bank, 1947
  315 Wyckoff Avenue
- Hamilton Federal Savings & Loan Association of Brooklyn, 1945, 1963
  498 Court Street; 413 86th Street
- Hammer, H., 1807
  Locksmith. 117 Court Street
- Hand & Fallesen, 1881
  Wheelwrights and carriage makers. Third Avenue, corner 22nd Street
- Hand, R.H., 1883
  Trunk and bag maker. 184 Fulton Street, corner Orange Street
- Handelsman, George, 1938
  Plumbing and heating. 77 Louisa Street
- Hanold, Charles H., 1869
  Butcher. 101 Atlantic Street
- Hanover Fire Insurance Company, 1865, 1880, 1881
  215 Montague Street; 45 Wall Street, New York
- Hansen, Clarence, 1930
  Tinsmith and roofer. 334 Ninth Street
- Hansen, George, 1879
  Butcher. 618 Third Avenue
- Hardee, J.E. Co., 1942
  Appliance dealer. Jamaica Avenue, cor. 145th St.
- Harden Bros., 1890
  Truckmen and riggers. 123 North Second St.
- Hardenburgh, G., 1882
  Painter. 299 Boradway, betw 9th & 10th Sts.
- Harding & Co., 1875
  Shoemaker. 317 Fulton St.
- Hardwick, John, 1869
  Metal worker. 92 Cranberry Street
- Hardy, Voorhees (& Co.), 1876, 1900, 1909
  Lumber dealers. Foot of North First Street; Metropolitan Avenue and Newtown Creek
- Harford, Matthew, 1878
  Fish monger. 15 & 17 Atlantic Market
- Harkins, James & Co., 1881
- Harkness, Wm., 1885
  Painter and paper hanger. 688, 690 & 692 Fulton Street
- Harley, James, 1884, 1887
  Plumber, gas and steam fitter. 288 Flatbush Avenue
- Harned, James B.'s Son, 1896
  Carpenter. 9 Marion Street
- Harned, O., 1891
  Cigar maker. 76 Broadway
- Harper, James, 1865
  Undertaker. 137 Court Street and 24 York Street
- Harring, John R., 1893
  Saddlery maker. 605 Atlantic Ave., near Flatbush Ave.
- Harris, George, 1880, 1882
  Stoves and heaters dealer. 689 Myrtle Avenue
- Harris, H.I.'s Son, 1893
  Glass dealer. 128 Broadway
- Hart, Jacob, 1877
  Carpenter and builder. 65 Henry Street, near Orange
- Hart & Smith, 1880
  Carpenter and builder. 63 Henry Street
- Harteau, H. & Co., 1869
  Masons material dealer. Flushing Avenue, bet. Clinton Ave. and Hamilton St.
- Hartman, H.S., 1885
  Plumber and gas fitter. 307 Sackett Street
- Hartman & Wakefield, 1871
  Plumber and gas fitter. 269 Court Street
- Hartmann, Geo., 1878
  Stoves and ranges dealer. 777 Myrtle Avenue
- Hartmann, J. & Schroeder, 1891
  Painter and paper hanger. 39 Melrose Street
- Hartstein, A., 1881
  Glass dealer. 1605 Fulton Street
- Hartye, Albert D., 1870, 1876, 1877
  Grocers. 427 Court Street, cor. of Third Place
- Hartye, E., Miss, 1878
  Milliner. 406 Court Street, corner of First Place
- Harvey & Halstead, 1876
  Furniture.
- Hatfield, Geo. E., 1899
  Roofing. 11 and 13 Classon Avenue
- Hatton & Doyle, Inc., 1933
  Agents [?]. 163 Remsen Street
- Hauck, Chas. J. & Son, 1898
  Fancy metal goods. 36, 38, & 40 Stagg St.
- Haviland & Sons, 1896
  Law and real estate. 399 Classon Ave.
- Hawkes, H., 1884, 1896
  Plumber, gas and steam fitter. 329, 425 Flatbush Avenue, near Park Place
- Hawkins, Chas. F., 1898
  Electrician, locksmith and bell hanger. 424 Fifth Avenue, near Eighth Street
- Hay & Scott, 1872
  Plumbers, steam and gas fitters. 319 Atlantic Ave., bet. Smith & Hoyt Sts.
- Hayden, E.P., 1884
  Jewelry. 412 Franklin Avenue
- Hayden, Martin J., 1932
  Plumber. 360 Bedford Avenue
- Hayes, Thomas, 1884
  Mason and builder. 324 Court Street
- Haym Salomon Home For The Aged, 1966
  2300 Cropsey Avenue
- Hays, Alanson, 1867, 1874-1876, 1884
  Mason and builder. 137, 207, 216 South Second Street; 206 Sixth Street
- Hazeltine & Co., 1879
  Wharfage. Foot of Atlantic Ave.
- Healy, Martin (& Son), 1881, 1896
  Plumbers and gas fitters. 7 Putnam Avenue
- Healy, P., 1892
  Plumber and gas fitter. 160 Penn Street, corner Lee Avenue
- Heaney, P.F. / Heaney Brothers, 1880, 1881, 1885, 1889
  "The Artist Hatter." 79 Fulton Street near York
- Heaney, W., 1887
  Hatter. 173 Fulton Street bet. High and Nassau Sts.
- Hearns, John, 1873, 1880
  Formerly Hearns & Ford. Carpenters and builders. Cor. Ryerson St. and Myrtle Ave.
- Heath, Chas. L., 1888
  Locksmith and bell hanger. 53 Greenpoint Avenue
- Hebrew Institute of Boro Park, 1965
  Hebrew school. 5000 Thirteenth Avenue
- Hedenberg & Co., 1876
  Propeller [tug boat]. 151 Front Street
- Hedge, Clarence, 1867
  Furnace dealer. 80 Myrtle Avenue
- Hegeman, Joseph, 1866
  Auctioneer. Willoughby, corner of Pearl St.
- Heidt, Louis (& Son), 1899
  Decorative glass and tiles. Cor. McKibben, Boerum and White Sts.
- Heik, Henry, 1887
  Grocer. Corner Third Avenue and 55th Street
- Heinbockel, John F. & Co. / New York Brewery, 1886
  62 & 64 Fulton, corner Hicks Street
- Heiser, F.C., 1887
  Heaters, roofing, and metal work. 650 Gates Avenue
- Heissenbuttel & Nelson, 1878, 1881
  Coal and wood dealer. Hamilton Avenue, near 3rd Avenue
- Heissenbuttel & Wiese, 1866
  Grocer. 11 and 13 Atlantic Street
- Heller, H., 1910
  Dress maker. Successor to Silverman & Heller. 284 So. 9th Street
- Hellman, S., 1920
  Carpet dealer. 4420 Third Ave.
- Hendrickson, J., 1870
  Shoemaker. Successor to T.J. Whitehouse. 176 & 178 Atlantic Street
- Hendrickson, John T., 1878
  Coal and wood dealer. Yard, cor. Flushing and Bedford Avenues
- Heney, Michael, 1898, 1900
  Horseshoer. 305 Degraw Street
- Heney, Philip, 1884
  Carpenter and builder. 85 Wyckoff Street
- Henjes, Henry, 1933
  Coal dealer. 1832 Cropsey Avenue
- Henry Engineering Co., circa early 20th century
  Engineers and machinists. Foot of 27th Street
- Herold, Casper, 1910
  Commission merchant. 143 Wallabout Market
- Herskowitz, Alfred, Rev., 1938
  Rabbi. 350 East 5th Street
- Herson, John J., 1879
  Plumber, gas and steam fitter. 158 Court St., opp. Dean St.
- Hettrick, W.J., 1870
  Grocer. 184 Myrtle Avenue
- Heuser & Hausleiter, 1896, 1898
  Glass stainers. 75, 77, & 79 Schermerhorn Street [formerly 217 Atlantic Avenue]
- Heusinger, Charles, 1889
  Mason and plasterer. 119 Miller Avenue
- Hews, A.H. & Co., 1889
  Potter. Long Island City
- Heydenreich Bros., 1892
  Pharmacists. 169 Atlantic Avenue, cor. Clinton St.
- Hickey, Kaplan & Witzek, 1907
  Liquor dealers. 5111 Fifth Avenue
- Hicks, Wm. C. & Co., 1883
  Grocers. 1109 Fulton St.
- Higbie, H.D., 1882
  Spice dealer. 43 Powers Street
- Higgins, Chas. M. & Co., 1903, 1910
  Inks and glue makers. 271 Ninth Street
- Higgins, Chas. S., 1886
  Laundry. Cor. Park and Clinton Avenues
- Higgins, John J., 1886
  Undertaker. 135 Jay Street
- Higgins, Matthew, 1889
  Metal worker. 33 & 34 York Street
- Hildreth & Bennett, 1876
  Real estate. 329 Cumberland Street
- Hildreth, James M. Jr.
  Real estate and coal. 329 Cumberland Street
- Hill, David H., 1883-1884
  Real estate, loans, and insurance. 393 Flatbush Avenue
- Hill, Frederick B.
  Builder. Miller Avenue, East New York
- Hill, Robert, 1875, 1898
  Heaters and house furnishings, roofing. 1791 Fulton Avenue; 27 Howard Ave. cor. of Madison St.
- Hillcrest Jewish Center, 1953
  Jewish school. Union Turnpike & Kent St., Jamaica
- Hilmer, Otto, 1885
  Merchant tailor. 187 DeKalb Avenue, cor. Carlton
- Hilzinger, A.J., 1893
  Roofing. 1844 Fulton Street
- Himer Stolps Co., 1910
  Builders. 2051 Clarendon Road
- Hirschfeld & Beck, 1908
  Liquor dealers. Brooklyn branch, corner Smith and Dean Sts.
- Hirt,George, 1884
  Household goods. 22 Sumner Avenue
- Hitchcock Realty Co., 1906
  Real estate and insurance. 1075A Myrtle Avenue [formerly 189 Montague Street]
- Hitchings, Benjamin G., 1905
  Planing and moulding mill. Eats 34th St. and Avenue H
- Hittleman, Edw. B. Brewery, 1932
  Brewery. Bushwick Place and Montrose Ave.
- Hoag,S.C. & Co., 1900
  Salt dealer. 2 to 24 Taylor St.
- Hobbs, Robert S. & Co., 1886, 1887, 1891
  Wallpaper manufacturer. 133 Columbia Street
- Hobby & Leeds/Doody Co., 1880, 1886, 1897
  Building materials. Hamilton Avenue and Gowanus Canal
- Hoben-Hunter-Feitner Company, 1921
  Lumber dealer. 1105 Metropolitan Avenue
- Hodge, Chas. E., 1881
  Knitting works. 106 Patchen Avenue, near Gates
- Hoellerer, Joseph, 1907
  Skylights and cornices. 91 Union Avenue, near Grand St.
- Hoff, Herman J., 1898
  Iron works. 556 & 558 Hamilton Avenue, near Third Ave.
- Hoffmann, Dr. Medicine Co., 1910
  Medicine manufacturer. 231 Hamburg Avenue
- Hoffmann, E., 1883
  Boot and shoe maker. 234 York Street
- Hoffmann, J.A. Co., 1922
  Multigraphs rented. 668 Forest Avenue
- Hoffmann, Otto G. & Co., 1909
  Awning makers. 368 Crescent Street, near Magenta St.
- Holland, Wm., 1873, 1876, 1883
  Metal worker. Myrtle Avenue, bet. Franklin Ave. & Skillman St.
- Hollands, E., 1883
  Locksmith. 752 Myrtle Avenue
- Hollingsworth, B.C., 1894
  Stables. Seventh Avenue & Union St.
- Holmes, D.S., 1865, 1890
  Publisher and stationer. 67 Fourth Street; 388 Bedford Avenue
- Holmes, Robert, 1871
  Locksmith. 59 Henry Street
- Holt & Company, 1890
  Rubber goods. 83 Broadway
- Holy Trinity, Church of the, 1883
- Home Insurance Company, 1880, 1882, 1943, 1949
  160 Atlantic Street; 42 Broadway; 180 Montague Street
- Hooker & Raymond, 1869
  Carpenter and builder. Corner Nassau and Adams Streets
- Hoop, Chas., 1885
  Shoemaker. 185 DeKalb Avenue
- Hopper, S.G. & Co., 1901
  Tinsmiths and roofers. 391 Crescent St. near Magenta St.
- Hopping, Ira W., 1890
  Mason and builder. 198 Prince Street
- Horan & Bro., 1878, 1880
  Plumbers and gas fitters. 1423 Fulton St., opp. Brooklyn Ave., and 727 Gates Ave.
- Horan, John F., 1898
  Contractor. 91 Dean Street
- Horgan, John A., 1869
  Mason and builder. Corner of Union and Hicks Streets
- Horn, Alfred E., 1895
  Bung maker. 1 to 11 Cumberland St., opposite Navy Yard
- Hornbuckel, Wm. B., 1888, 1890
  Painter and decorator. 865 Myrtle Avenue
- Horne, William, 1908
  Shipsmith. 411 Van Brunt St.
- Horre, Wm., 1881
  Tug boat (propeller). 207 Huntington St.
- Horton, Hubbell & Co. / T.K. Horton & Co., 1877, 1879, 1881, 1882, 1893
  Dry goods. 394 & 396 Fulton Street and 17 Smith Street
- Horton, Joseph H., 1873, 1880, 1889
  Painter and decorator. 389 Myrtle Avenue
- Horton & Sons, 1859
  Dry goods. 279 Fulton St., bet. Tillary & Johnson
- Horton's Carbonic Gas Service, 1937
  Gas service. 1370 Brooklyn Ave.
- Hosford, James B., 1889
  Plumber and gas fitter. 422 Gates Avenue
- Hosford, William J., 1869, 1874, 1877
  Plumber and gas fitter. 85 Fulton Avenue; 456, 460 Fulton St., near Hoyt Street
- Hotaling, W.G., 1875
  Carpenter and builder. 251 Tompkins Avenue
- Houchin, Alfred W., 1891, 1893
  Soap and candle maker. 11 Vine Street
- Hough, J.H. & S.L., 1875
  Carpenter and builder. 237 Nostrand Avenue
- House and Home Company, The, 1917
  Real estate. 105 Flatbush Avenue
- Houston & M'Namara, 1863
  Plumbers and gas fitters. 92 Myrtle Avenue
- Howard Clothes, 1954
  Clothing sellers. 1558 Pitkin Avenue
- Howell, James Jr., 1862
  Iron works. 289 Adams Street
- Howell & Saxtan, 1887
  Iron railing manufacturer. 353 & 355 Adams Street
- Hoyt, A., 1880
  Robes. 42 Bedford Avenue
- Hoyt & Teale, 1872, 1874, 1876
  Clothiers. 607, 609 & 611 Fulton Street
- Huber, Frederick W., 1925
  Bakers' supplies. 314-316 Park Avenue
- Hudson, George & Son's, 1866
  Plumbers and painters. Cor. Fulton & York Street
- Hudson, T.T., 1888
  Butcher. 161 Broadway, near 5th Street
- Hudson, W.T., 1905
  Plumber and gas fitter. 411 Nostrand Avenue
- Huebner, E., 1911-1912
  Ladies neckwear. 333 St. Nicholas Avenue
- Huelle, John E., 1897
  Printer. 4 Sumner Avenue
- Hueston, James, 1887
  Plumber, gas and steam fitter. 6 Hoyt Street, corner Fulton
- Huggins, Wm. / Wm. Huggins' Son, 1873, 1880
  Boots and shoes dealer. 114, 125 Bridge Street, cor. of Prospect
- Hughes, John, 1877
  Butcher. 329 Court Street
- Hughes, P., 1880
  Mason and plasterer. 953 Pacific Street
- Huhn & Zipfel / Joseph Huhn, 1866, 1872,1879
  Furniture makers. 29, 58 Court Street
- Hulin & Hedges, 1892
  Carpenters and builders. 277 Twelfth Street
- Hultgren, I.W., 1896
  Hardware and home goods. Successor J.V.B. Bergen. 1310 Third Avenue
- Hummel, George, 1915
  Furniture and carpets. 1497-1499-1501-1503 Myrtle Ave.
- Hunt, Mansfield, 1887
  Carpenter and builder. 139 South Fifth Street
- Hunter, James W., 1869
  Liquor importer. 72 Fulton Street
- Huntington & Du Bois, 1863, 1867
  Gentleman's clothing. 322 Fulton Street, between Pierrepont and Motague Streets
- Huntington, H.L., 1859-1860
  Gentleman's clothing. 139 Atlantic Street
- Hunton-Cutting Co., 1905
  Real estate. 75 Sixth Avenue
- Hurth, C., 1894
  Upholsterer. 416 Atlantic Ave., near Bond St.
- Hussey, James, 1876
  Plumber, steam and gas fitter. 149 Hamilton Avenue
- Husted & Clark, 1867
  Coal and wood dealer. Cor. Bedford and Flushing Avenues
- Huston & Koomas, 1933
  Painters and decorators. 863 St. Johns Place
- Hutchinson, Fred'k A., 1884
  Plumber and gas fitter. 334 Myrtle Avenue
- Huth, F., 1890
  Harness maker. 534 Grand Street
- Hyde, E. Belcher, 1910, 1924
  Map publishers. 5 Beekman St., New York; 97 Liberty St.; Warehouse in Brooklyn
- Hygrade Provision Co., 1926
  Cured meats. 146-154 Broadway
- Ideal Book Service, 1961
  Book dealer. 108 Midwood Street
- Ideal Heating Co., 1919
  Boiler makers. 915 Gates Avenue
- Igoe Brothers, 1911
  Wire makers. 61-73 Metropolitan Avenue
- Imperial Knitting Mill, 1895
  Clothing makers. 36 South First Street
- Incandescent Burner Company, 1900
  Lighting installers. 322 Fulton Street
- Inch & King, 1897
  Plumber, gas and steam fitter. 179 Ralph Avenue
- Independent Salt Co., 1910, 1911, 1914
  2 to 24 Taylor St.
- India Rubber Roofing Co., 1870
  74 Fulton Street
- India Wharf Brewing Co., 1896
  32 to 60 Hamilton Ave.
- Inter-County Title Guaranty and Mortgage Company, 1947
  166 Remsen Street
- Internal Revenue, 1863-1865, 1868
  Hamilton Building, 14 Court Street; 365 Fulton Street
- International Sunshine Society, 1907, 1909
  Southern Division, New York State. 121 Hooper Street; 96 Fifth Avenue, New York
- Ireland, Thos. H., 1899
  Undertaker. 177 North Sixth St.
- Iron Clad Gravel Roofing Co., 1878
  Roofers. 481 Vanderbilt Ave.
- Iron Clad Manufacturing Company, 1879, 1906, 1910
  Manufacturing goods. 204-206 Varet Street
- Irving Academy, 1883
  School
- Irving Civic Association, 1922
  384 Weirfeld Street; (meets at) Irving Avenue & Cornelia St.
- Island Floor Covering & Bedding Store, 1944
  Store. 2123 Mermaid Avenue
- Island Florist, The, 1944
  Florist. 1510 Mermaid Avenue
- Island Musical Shop, 1944
  Music store. 2025 Mermaid Avenue
- Italian Cement & Gravel Roofing Co., 1875
  Roofing Co.
- Jackson, 1875
  Printer. 408 & 410 Kent Avenue
- Jackson & Cowenhoven, 1889,1900
  Hardware. 639 Fulton Street and 50 Rockwell Place
- Jacob Brothers, 1898
  Piano makers. 195 Broadway
- Jacob, Robert, 1880
  Plumber and gas fitter. 255 Classon Ave. [formerly 405 Bedford Ave.]
- Jacobs, Geo. P. & Co., 1886
  Plumbers, steam and gas fitters; engineers. 369 and 371 Kent Avenue, 23 and 25 South Sixth Street
- Jacobs, Harris, 1885
  Glass dealer. 237 Smith Street
- Jacobs & McCafferty, 1897
  Paint makers. Bedford Ave. and North 15th Street
- Jacobs, William, 1872
  Draper and tailor. 152 (old 142) Fulton Street, cor. Middagh opp. Sands; 3 York Street
- Jacobson, A.C., 1879
  Hatter. 337 Fulton Street
- Jacobson, J. & Co., 1870
  Hatter. 4 Fulton Avenue
- Jacobson & Kahn, 1872
  Hatters and furriers. 425 Fulton Street
- Jacobson & Verity, 1889
  Lumber dealers. 93 Plymouth Street
- Jacobson's Travel Bureau, 1934
  Travel agent. 226 Flatbush Avenue
- Jamaica Improvement / Long Island Railroad, 1913
  Railroad. 1964 Broadway
- James, G.S., 1883
  Plumber
- James, John F. (& Son), 1877, 1891
  Successor to Wyckoff and James. Auctioneer, real estate and insurance. 189 Montague Street
- James, T.M. & Co., 1882
  Ladies dress goods. 372 & 374 Fulton St.
- Janson, Albert, 1890, 1901
  Carpenter and builder. 78th Street cor. 4th Ave.
- Jeffards, E. & Sons, 1899
  Horseshoers. Union Lane, Myrtle Avenue, bet. Adams and Pearl Sts.
- Jefferson Brass Foundry, 1901
  Brass foundry. 209 and 211 King Street
- Jefferson, E.S., 1890
  Painter. 355 Graham Avenue
- Jenkins & Gillies, 1870
  Carpenters and builders. 372 South 5th St., bet. 10th and 11th
- Jenkins, William, 1889
  Painter. 534 DeKalb Avenue, near Bedford Avenue
- Jersey, I.E., 1892
  Carpenter and builder. 12 Berkeley Place
- Jessup & Childs, 1878
  Paint importer. 225 Pearl St., cor. of Platt
- Jewell Brothers, 1870
  Floor dealer. 4 Fulton Street
- Jewish Ministers & Cantors Association of America, 1937
  National Palace Building, Houston and 2nd, New York
- Jewish War Veterans of U.S., 1946
  Major Philip Lehman Post No. 50. 529 Surf Avenue
- Jimmerson, A.S., 1873
  Veterinary surgeon. 146 Huron Street
- Joerger, Charles, 1889
  Carpenter. 261 Ellery St., near Sumner Ave.
- Johnson, Anthony, 1866
  Stone dealer. John Street, bet. Jay and Bridge Streets
- Johnson, Arthur & Co., 1901
  Athletic outfitters. Successors to Johnson & Stoutenburgh. 55 West 42nd Street, New York
- Johnson, C.L., 1883
  Carpenter and builder. 56 to 63 Ninth Street
- Johnson, Chas. E., 1896
  Carpenter and builder. 1850 Fulton Street
- Johnson, Carl J., 1936
  191 St. Marks Avenue
- Johnson, D.E. & Co., 1884
  Tailors. 767 Fulton Street
- Johnson, J., 1876, 1879
  Furniture dealer. 255 Columbia St., bet. President and Carroll Sts.
- Johnson, J., 1890
  Painter. Brighton Beach depot
- Johnson, Jere Jr. & Co., 1923
  Real estate. 193 Montague Street
- Johnson, John, 1919
  Menswear. 879 Flatbush Avenue, near Church Avenue
- Johnson & Miller, 1868
  Auctioneers and real estate. 157 Montague Street, near Court St.
- Johnson, R., 1885
  Tailor. 55 Bond Street, cor. Schermerhorn
- Johnson & Spader, 1860
  Lumber dealer. Kent Avenue, cor. Hewes Street
- Jonas & Levison, 1906
  Paper goods. 624 Myrtle Avenue
- Jones, Albert J. / Jones & Ingram, 1890
  Builder and decorator. Clarkson St. & Flatbush Ave.
- Jones, I.P., 1898
  Shipwright. Foot of 27th Street
- Jones, J.W., 1866
  Painter. 219 Fulton Street, cor. Sprague's Place
- Jones, R., 1882
  Carriages and wagons. 161-165 Nassau St. and 182-188 Bridge St.
- Jones, S.B., 1882-1883
  Haberdashery. 309 Fulton Street
- Jones, Thomas Decorative Glass Co., 1896
  Decorative glass. Hudson Ave. and Concord St.
- Jones, Wm. D. & Co., 1865